Guide to the Bureau of Military Information, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Bureau of Military Information, Yale University, records
1942-1947
RU 816
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
11.5
(26 boxes)
The records consist of administrative files, memoranda, reserve program information, correspondence, letters of recommendation, and student files documenting the operations of the Yale Bureau of Military Information.
Yale University. Bureau of Military Information
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 42-A (YRG 42-A), Records of military training programs at Yale.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Biographical / Historical
The Yale Bureau of Military Information served as a liaison between Yale students and the U.S. Armed Forces.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of administrative files, memoranda, reserve program information, correspondence, letters of recommendation, and student files documenting the operations of the Yale Bureau of Military Information.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by subject.
Soldiers -- Education, Non-military -- United States; Universities and colleges -- Administration; World War, 1939-1945 -- Education and the war; World War, 1939-1945 -- War work -- Schools; World War, 1939-1945 -- United States; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Bureau of Military Information
- Administrative and student records, circa 1942-1947; Accession 19ND-A-173
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2023.
  - Joint College Procurment Committee (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Office of Naval Officer Procurement (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Navy V-1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Navy V-5 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Navy V-7 (Box 1, Folder 5 - 6)
  - Navy V-12 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - HV-P Directive (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Army - Recruiting Directives (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Enlisted Reserve Corps - Information (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Army - ROTC (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Army Air Force Information (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Army Air Force Meteorology (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Army Signal Corps (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Marine Corps (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Coast Guard Information (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Army Specialized Training Program (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - American Council on Educational Bulletins (Box 2, Folder 18 - 19)
  - Red Cross and War-Time Medical Services (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Comdssion on Preparation for War Service (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Washing ton Interviews (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - E.D.S. and B.M.I. trips (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous B.M.I. reports (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Yale and the War: policy (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Publications (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Additional Copies - Yale War Service (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Releases to Yale News (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Top Service and Civilian Personnel (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Navy - General Information (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Navy V-1 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Navy V-4 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Navy V-5 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Navy V-7 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Navy SV-7 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Navy V - l l (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Navy V-12 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Navy H-VF (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - A-v (S) (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - E-V(P), O-V(F), SC-V(P), H-V(P) (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Navy - Annapolis (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Army
    - Army (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - General (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Foreign Areas (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Japanese School (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - E.R.C. (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - A-12 (ASTP) (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Signal Corps (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Medical Corps (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Mountain troops (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Opportunities at non-commissioned level (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Civilian Opportunities (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Classification System (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - West Point (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Opportunities for Limited Servicemen (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Opportunities for O.C.S. and Officer Schools (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Army Specialist Corps (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Commisions FSC (Box 4, Folder 58 - 59)
  - Allied Armies
    - Army Air Crew- (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Army Air Force - Ground Crew (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - AAF Ground Crew - Meteorology (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - AAF Glider (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - AAF - Opportunites for ClCS (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - AAF - Opportunities at non-commissioned levels (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Civil Aeronomics Administration (Box 4, Folder 66 - 67)
    - Coast Guard (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Merchant Marine (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Conscientious Objectors (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Opportunities in Canadian Army (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - American Field Service (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Physical Standards
    - Navy (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - Army (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - Selective Service (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - College War Programs
    - Yale (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - Brown University Bulletins (Box 5, Folder 77)
    - Harvard (Box 5, Folder 78)
    - Columbia bulletins and Training in International Administration (Box 5, Folder 79)
    - University of Wisconsin bulletins (Box 5, Folder 80)
  - Navy correspondence and letters
    - Washington Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 81)
    - New York Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 82)
    - Inter-office Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 83)
    - Boston Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 84)
    - New Haven Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 85)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 86)
  - Navy D.V.P. (Box 5, Folder 87)
  - Naval Reserve
    - A - D (Box 5, Folder 88)
    - E - N (Box 5, Folder 89)
    - O - Z (Box 5, Folder 90)
  - Navy V-1
    - Student Records (Box 5, Folder 91)
    - HV (P) (Box 5, Folder 92)
    - Student Records Class 1944 (Box 5, Folder 93)
    - Student Records Class 1945 (Box 6, Folder 94)
    - Student Records Class 1945W (Box 6, Folder 95)
  - Navy V-5
    - Naval Aviation Information (Box 6, Folder 96)
    - Student Records (Box 6, Folder 97)
  - Navy V-7
    - Class of 1942 (Box 6, Folder 98)
    - Class of 1943
      - A - I (Box 6, Folder 99)
      - J - Z (Box 6, Folder 100)
    - Class of 1944 (Box 6, Folder 101)
    - Graduate and Miscellaneous Schools (Box 6, Folder 102)
  - Navy SV-7
    - Recommendations (Box 6, Folder 103)
    - Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 104)
  - Navy V-12 (Box 7, Folder 105)
    - 45W (Box 7, Folder 106)
    - 46 (Box 7, Folder 107)
  - Naval Supply Corps (Box 7, Folder 108)
  - Naval Intelligence (Box 7, Folder 109)
  - Coast Guard - general information (Box 7, Folder 110)
  - Army
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 111)
    - Correspondence Officer Procurement FSC (Box 7, Folder 112)
    - Medical Administrative Corps (Box 7, Folder 113)
    - Ski Troops (Box 7, Folder 114)
    - Letters of recommendation (Box 7, Folder 115)
  - Army Specialized Training Program (Box 7, Folder 116)
    - ASTP medical (Box 7, Folder 117)
  - Army Enlisted Reserve Corps
    - ASTP First Service Command (Box 7, Folder 118)
  - Washington D.C. Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 119)
    - 1943 (Box 7, Folder 120 - 121)
    - General Correspondence
      - A-J (Box 7, Folder 122)
      - K-R (Box 7, Folder 123)
      - S-Z (Box 8, Folder 124)
    - 1944 (Box 8, Folder 125)
    - 1945 Correspondence
      - A - G (Box 8, Folder 126)
      - H - Q (Box 8, Folder 127)
      - R - Z (Box 8, Folder 128)
    - 1945W Correspondence
      - A - G (Box 8, Folder 129)
      - H - L (Box 8, Folder 130)
      - M - Z (Box 8, Folder 131)
      - 1946 and 1947 (Box 8, Folder 132)
    - Graduate and Miscellaneous Schools (Box 8, Folder 133)
  - Army Signal Corps (Box 8, Folder 134)
  - Army Air Forces
    - General Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 135)
    - Civil Aeronomics Administration CPT training (Box 8, Folder 136)
    - Meteorology
      - General Information (Box 8, Folder 137)
      - A - D (Box 8, Folder 138)
      - E - M (Box 9, Folder 139)
      - N - Z (Box 9, Folder 140)
    - Student Records
      - A - G (Box 9, Folder 141)
      - H - M (Box 9, Folder 142)
      - N - Z (Box 9, Folder 143)
  - Marines
    - Washington Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 144)
    - Boston Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 145)
    - New London Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 146)
    - General Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 147)
    - 1942 (Box 9, Folder 148)
  - Marine Corps
    - 1943 (Box 9, Folder 149)
    - 1944 (Box 9, Folder 150)
    - 1945 (Box 9, Folder 151)
    - 1945W (Box 9, Folder 152)
    - 1946 (Box 10, Folder 153)
    - Reserve (Box 10, Folder 154)
  - General Recommendation (Box 10, Folder 155)
  - F.B.I. (Box 10, Folder 156)
  - Inquiries Armed Forces
    - A - D (Box 10, Folder 157)
    - E - H (Box 10, Folder 158)
    - I - M (Box 10, Folder 159)
    - N - Q (Box 11, Folder 160)
    - R - T (Box 11, Folder 161)
    - U - Z (Box 11, Folder 162)
  - B.M.I. General Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 163)
  - American Field Service Bulletins (Box 11, Folder 164)
  - Enlistments in Navy V-1, V-5, V-7 and V-12: Marine Corps Classes of 1943, 1944, 1945, 1945W (Box 12, Folder 165)
  - Enlistments in Army Reserved Corps Air Force E.R.C. Classes of 1943, 1944, 1945, 1945W, 1946, 1947 (Box 13, Folder 166)
  - Statistics
    - Overall (Box 14, Folder 167)
    - Navy (Box 14, Folder 168)
    - Grand Navy Lists (Box 14, Folder 169)
    - Army Enlisted Reserve Corps (Box 14, Folder 170 - 171)
    - Class of 1942
      - V- 7 (Box 14, Folder 172)
      - N.R.O.T. C. (Box 14, Folder 173)
      - Marines (Box 14, Folder 174)
      - R.O.T.C. (Box 14, Folder 175)
      - Probationary Commissions (Box 14, Folder 176)
    - Class of 1943
      - E.R.C. Statistics (Box 14, Folder 177)
      - E.R.C. Enlistment (Box 14, Folder 178)
      - A.E.R.C. Recommendations (Box 14, Folder 179)
      - Army Air Force (Box 14, Folder 180)
      - R.O.T.C. (Box 14, Folder 181)
      - V- 5 (Box 14, Folder 182)
      - V- 7 (Box 14, Folder 183)
      - Naval Science (Box 14, Folder 184)
      - Navy Probationary Commissions (Box 14, Folder 185)
      - Marines Class (Box 14, Folder 186)
      - War Industry Deferred (Box 14, Folder 187)
      - Class of 1943 (Box 14, Folder 188)
    - Class of 1944
      - E.R.C. - To Active Duty (Box 15, Folder 189)
      - E.R.C. Enlistments (Box 15, Folder 190)
      - E.R.C. Letters of Recommendation (Box 15, Folder 191)
      - E A C. Statistics (Box 15, Folder 192)
      - R.O.T.C. (Box 15, Folder 193)
      - Army Air Force (Box 15, Folder 194)
      - Meteorology (Box 15, Folder 195)
      - V-1 and V-7 (Box 15, Folder 196)
      - V-5 (Box 15, Folder 197)
      - Marines (Box 15, Folder 198)
      - N.R.O.T.C. (Box 15, Folder 199)
      - War Industry (Box 15, Folder 200)
      - Bible (Box 15, Folder 201)
    - Class of 1945
      - E.R.C. - To Active Duty (Box 15, Folder 202)
      - A.E.R.C. Enlistment (Box 15, Folder 203)
      - E. R. C. Letters of Recommends tion (Box 15, Folder 204)
      - E.R.C. Statistics (Box 15, Folder 205)
      - Army Air Force (Box 15, Folder 206)
      - R.O.T.C. (Box 15, Folder 207)
      - Meterology (Box 15, Folder 208)
      - V-1 (Box 15, Folder 209)
      - V-5 (Box 15, Folder 210)
      - Marines (Box 15, Folder 211)
      - N.R.O.T.C (Box 15, Folder 212)
      - War Industry Class (Box 15, Folder 213)
      - Bibles (Box 16, Folder 214)
    - Class of 1945W
      - E.R.C. - To Active Duty (Box 16, Folder 215)
      - A.E.R.C. Enlistment (Box 16, Folder 216)
      - E.R.C. Letters of Recommendation (Box 16, Folder 217)
      - Army Air Force (Box 16, Folder 218)
      - R.O.T.C. (Box 16, Folder 219)
      - Prospective Students (Box 16, Folder 220)
      - V-1 (Box 16, Folder 221)
      - V-5 (Box 16, Folder 222)
      - Marines (Box 16, Folder 223)
      - N.R.O.T.C. (Box 16, Folder 224)
      - V-1 (Box 16, Folder 225)
      - War Zndustry (Box 16, Folder 226)
      - Statistics (Box 16, Folder 227)
    - Class of 1946
      - E.R.C. Classes (Box 16, Folder 228 - 229)
      - E.R.C. Class Recommendation (Box 16, Folder 230)
      - Air Corps Enlisted Reserve (Box 16, Folder 231)
      - V-6 Naval Reserve (Box 16, Folder 232)
      - V-12 (Box 16, Folder 233)
      - Civilians (Box 16, Folder 234)
      - Bible (Box 16, Folder 235)
    - Class of 1947
      - E.R.C. Call (Box 16, Folder 236)
      - V6 Naval Reserve (Box 16, Folder 237)
      - Bible (Box 16, Folder 238)
      - Notices from DUH (Box 16, Folder 239)
    - Navy
      - Class V-1 (Box 17, Folder 240)
      - Enlistment Navy V-l Data (Box 17, Folder 241)
      - Class V-5 lists (Box 17, Folder 242)
      - Class V-7 (Box 17, Folder 243)
      - Class SV-7 (Box 17, Folder 244)
      - Class V-12 (Box 17, Folder 245)
      - Probationary Committee (Box 17, Folder 246)
      - Naval Intelligence (Box 17, Folder 247)
      - N.R.O.T.C. (Box 17, Folder 248)
    - Army
      - Army Enlisted Reserve (Box 17, Folder 249)
      - Air Force Enlisted Reserve (Box 17, Folder 250)
      - Army Air Force (Box 17, Folder 251)
      - Japanese School (Box 17, Folder 252)
      - Meteotology (Box 17, Folder 253)
    - Marines
      - Marines (Box 17, Folder 254)
      - Marine Certificates (Box 17, Folder 255)
      - Active Duty Statement (Box 17, Folder 256)
      - Marines (Box 17, Folder 257)
  - American Field Service (Box 17, Folder 258)
  - Medical Students (Box 17, Folder 259)
  - Pre-Medical Students (Box 17, Folder 260)
  - Miscellaneous
    - War Industry (Box 18, Folder 261)
    - General Warning Lists (Box 18, Folder 262)
    - Reservists Dropped for Low Stand (Box 18, Folder 263)
    - Resignstions for Military Service (Box 18, Folder 264)
    - B.M.I. Appointment Schedules (Box 18, Folder 265)
  - Registration for War Service
    - A - L (Box 18, Folder 266)
    - M - Z (Box 18, Folder 267)
    - 1944
      - A - K (Box 18, Folder 268)
      - L - Z (Box 19, Folder 269)
    - 1945A
      - A - K (Box 19, Folder 270)
    - 1945 E, S
      - A - K (Box 19, Folder 271)
      - L - Z (Box 19, Folder 272)
    - 1945W
      - Service and B.M.I. interviews
        - A - H (Box 19, Folder 273)
        - I - Z (Box 19, Folder 274)
      - Counselor and B.M.I. interviews
        - A - Bo (Box 19, Folder 275)
        - Br - Da (Box 20, Folder 276)
        - De - F (Box 20, Folder 277)
        - G - H (Box 20, Folder 278)
        - I - L (Box 20, Folder 279)
        - M (Box 20, Folder 280)
        - N - R (Box 20, Folder 281)
        - S (Box 20, Folder 282)
        - T - Z (Box 20, Folder 283)
  - Navy Questionnaires
    - A - E (Box 20, Folder 284)
    - F - K (Box 21, Folder 285)
    - L - Q (Box 21, Folder 286)
    - R - Z (Box 21, Folder 287)
    - Supplementary Informattion
      - Class 1943 (Box 21, Folder 288)
      - Class 1944 V-7 (Box 21, Folder 289)
      - Class 1945 V-1 (Box 21, Folder 290)
      - Class 1945W V-1 (Box 21, Folder 291)
    - Miscellaneous Classes (Box 22, Folder 292)
    - Marine Questionnaires (Box 22, Folder 293)
    - Student Questionnaires
      - A (Box 22, Folder 294)
      - B (Box 22, Folder 295)
      - D (Box 22, Folder 296)
      - E (Box 22, Folder 297)
      - F (Box 23, Folder 298)
      - G (Box 23, Folder 299)
      - H (Box 23, Folder 300 - 301)
      - J (Box 23, Folder 302)
      - K (Box 23, Folder 303)
      - L (Box 23, Folder 304)
      - M (Box 23, Folder 305)
      - N (Box 23, Folder 306)
      - O (Box 24, Folder 307)
      - P (Box 24, Folder 308)
      - Q (Box 24, Folder 309)
      - R (Box 24, Folder 310)
      - S (Box 24, Folder 311)
      - T (Box 24, Folder 312)
      - U (Box 24, Folder 313)
      - V (Box 24, Folder 314)
      - W (Box 24, Folder 315)
      - Y (Box 24, Folder 316)
      - Z (Box 24, Folder 317)
    - Reports of Physical Examination
      - Class 1943 (Box 24, Folder 318)
      - Class 1944 (Box 25, Folder 319 - 320)
        - Failed Physical, Withdrawn, NOM (Box 25, Folder 321 - 322)
      - Class 1945
        - Failed Physical, Withdrawn, NOM (Box 25, Folder 323 - 324)
      - Class 1945W - WF
        - Failed Physical, Withdrawn, NOM (Box 25, Folder 325)
        - Failed Physical, Withdrawn, NOM (Box 26, Folder 326 - 327)
    - Other Colleges enlisted into A.E.R.C. at Yale University (Box 26, Folder 328)